Senpai.
Are you awake?
Good morning, Sakura.
Yes, good morning, Senpai.
Sorry, Sakura.
I should be helping
with breakfast.
Don't worry about that.
You were up late
again, weren't you?
Don't be silly.
That's no excuse.
Let me take care of it, Senpai.
If you leave the storehouse in this
state, Fujimura-sensei will scold you.
Good point.
Guess I'll take you
up on that offer, then.
Great.
I'll be waiting for you, Senpai.
Falling asleep before
finishing shows that I lack focus.
In the face of absolute despair
That nearly burned
our hearts away
You still found the
courage to smile
Like you accepted it all
I lost my voice
And the things I wanted to say
But every time I
fell to my knees
I stood up and kept walking
We were looking for
the ideal white future
Our one and only hope
Now I may be left with nothing
But these raging
emotions that have
Nowhere to go
Still, I'll look for a new dawn
With more than one right answer
I won't stop
Until I find it
A Winter's Day, A Fateful Night
In other news,
the government
announced this morning
Perfect.
That it has approved the merger
between KK Aviation and TT Airways.
There were concerns that the
proposed deal would violate antitrust laws,
but it was given the
green light after the two
companies agreed to
scale down their operations.
I feel terrible making
you do all this, Sakura.
It's no trouble at all.
I do it because I want to.
Morning, Fuji-nee.
Morning!
Let's eat!
Let's eat.
Senpai?
Th-This isn't soy sauce!
Other sauces don't belong on rice with
grated yams! Especially not oyster sauce!
I switched the labels on the
bottles earlier! Gotcha good, huh?
Yay!
Who pulls a stunt like that
first thing in the morning?
You're turning twenty-five
this year, for heaven's sake.
Guess you'll always be
the same old Fuji-nee.
You had it coming!
This is payback for yesterday!
Senpai, have some tea.
I thought you
seemed awfully quiet.
You've been planning
this ever since then?
Damn straight.
I spent a whole lot of time that I
should have spent grading tests.
So I gotta run, or I'll never
get them done in time!
Thanks for breakfast!
See you at school!
Don't go back to sleep
and wind up late, okay?
Well, I'm outta here!
Your cooking was as
delicious as ever, Sakura-chan!
It was nothing, Fujimura-sensei.
Soy
Oyster
Damn that Fuji-nee.
Does being the landlord's daughter
give her the right to eat here every day?
She's no better
than a freeloader.
Did you do something
to upset her yesterday?
I accidentally called her
by that one nickname.
Then you deserved it, Senpai.
You should be more careful.
You know she hates it
when you call her that.
- Tokyo - Gas Leak in
Shinto Business District
In our next story,
workers in a Shinto business
district office building were hospitalized
after passing
out late last night.
According to the
police statement,
Tokyo
Gas Leak in Shinto
Business District
the victims were all found
with apparent hypoxia, which
has led them to suspect a
possible gas leak as the cause.
However, given that a similar
incident occurred last month,
Hear that? Another
gas leak in Shinto.
They are also investigating
a possible connection.
That's messed up.
We need to be careful too.
Don't worry.
I always double-check the
gas valve, so we'll be fine.
No, not about that.
Well, work hard
at club practice.
About that, Senpai...
Maybe you could
stop by the dojo?
I have to go to the student
council office this morning.
O-Oh, of course.
I'm sorry. Forget I asked.
Well, I should get going.
Look forward to
dinner tonight, okay?
The school's budgetary allocations
are completely unbalanced.
Yeah, athletic clubs get the lion's share
of the budget, and the rest get the crumbs.
Indeed.
As a result, the facilities available
to non-athletic clubs are in disrepair.
They've given zero thought
to resolving our heater issues.
You mean this isn't
the only broken one?
Indeed.
As I thought, it's
just showing its age.
Can you fix it, Emiya?
I can.
Really?
It won't take long, so
could you wait outside?
Of course. I'll get
out of your way.
Okay, then.
There are two spots where the
heating element is about to break.
The heat transfer pipes
should be good for a while.
I can patch the power cord
with electrical tape for now.
Tohsaka...
Tohsaka?
Well, if it isn't the
student council president.
Already up and
patrolling the school?
Or are you doing
maintenance on the club rooms?
Either way, I see you're
as diligent as always.
And what are you
up to this morning?
Why are you here so early
when you aren't in any clubs?
I just felt like it.
It's fixed, Issei.
Oh, sorry.
I asked you for help, but you
ended up doing all the work.
My bad, Emiya.
Where's the next one?
We don't have all day.
It's in the A/V room.
They said it had been
acting up for a while, and now
it looks like it's reached
the end of its lifespan.
If it's dead, I can't fix that.
You're better off
buying a new one.
While that's true, I'd appreciate it if
you could take a look at it anyway.
It looked dead to me, but you might
be able to tell if it's just pretending.
Okay. I'll give it a shot.
You're an early riser, Tohsaka.
The art club's heater will
have to wait until lunchtime.
Yeah.
You're quite the busy
bee this morning, Emiya.
I was wondering what you'd
been up to after quitting the club.
You're the student council
president's errand boy, eh?
If you need anything on your
end, just let me know, Shinji.
If it's something I
can help with, I will.
Maintaining bows was
never your strong suit, after all.
Mind your own business.
You're not part of the club anymore, so
don't show your face near the dojo again!
Is he serious? Did he
forget that he was the
one who drove you
out in the first place?
It's okay. That's
just how he is.
You get used to it eventually.
Do you, now?
You do.
Uh-oh. Fujimura-sensei is
about to come barreling in.
All right! I made it!
Good morning, class!
I'll take attendance now.
Emiya, if you don't eat your
lunch soon, you won't get to.
It's okay. I'm almost done.
The heaters are one thing, but you didn't
have to agree to fix personal items too.
Don't worry about it.
Like they say, in for a
penny, in for a pound.
There's such a thing
as being too considerate.
Being helpful is all well and good,
but you should really learn to say no.
You take "turn no one
away" too far, Emiya.
Do I seem like that
much of a pushover?
You're leaving yourself open to being
taken advantage of by the unscrupulous.
Surely you could turn people
down every once in a while.
What're you talking about?
Helping others is a good deed.
That's not something the heir to a
temple should be complaining about.
I'm just saying that you
take it too far, Emiya.
If you keep going like
this, you'll burn out.
Duly noted.
Okay, all done!
If you don't summon
yours soon, you'll die,
Onii-chan.
Of all the times
to come home late!
I said in homeroom that it hasn't
been safe in town lately, remember?
Um... Something came up.
Do you get that
from Kiritsugu-san?
I worry about what'll
happen to you if you keep
spending all your time
trying to help people.
Excuse me, Fujimura-sensei?
Has Senpai always been this way?
Yeah, for as long
as I've known him.
Shirou just doesn't have it in
him to ignore people in need.
"Comfort the afflicted, and
afflict the comfortable", you know?
When he was a kid, he
wrote in an essay, "When
I grow up, I wanna be
a champion of justice!"
Wow, he must have been adorable.
And whose fault
do you think that is?
When kids grow up around immature adults,
they get funny ideas in their heads.
If you don't like it, cook
your own damn food for once.
What?
You're going to make me cry!
Sakura-chan, fill 'er up!
Trace on.
Tracing fundamental structure.
Tracing auxiliary components.
Altering fundamental structure.
Reinforcing
auxiliary components.
Damn, failed again.
I can't believe that I still
can't do something this basic.
I'm gonna be a novice forever.
I just don't get it.
How do I become a
champion of justice?
Sakura, wait a second.
Yes?
What happened to your wrist?
Shinji again?
What's he thinking, raising
his hand against his little sister?
N-No, that's not it, Senpai!
I, um, got this when
I tripped and fell.
You can't get a bruise
like that from tripping.
I knew it.
My brother had nothing
to do with this, I swear!
I got hurt by
myself. That's all.
Well, if you say so.
I'll leave it at that.
Thank you. And
I'm sorry, Senpai.
Why are you apologizing?
It's Shinji who's to blame.
Do I smell your famous
rolled omelets, Shirou?
What's up, Emiya?
Let's eat.
Sorry, Issei. I'm going to
eat in the cafeteria today.
That's unusual. Did
something happen?
Not really.
Excuse me.
Is Ryuudou here?
I am, sir.
What is it, Kuzuki-sensei?
Change
A Set
B Set
Lunch Lady Set
Chef's Special
Winter Special Oden Set
Miso Ramen
Soy Sauce Ramen
Sliced Pork Ramen
Rice Set
Extra Noodles
Fried Rice
Curry Rice
Pork Cutlet Curry
Beef Bowl
Pork Cutlet Bowl
Extra Rice
Miso Soup Set
Going with the chef's special
for lunch today, are we?
Not eating with the prez today?
Nah.
Say, Mitsuzuri...
Has Sakura seemed
okay to you lately?
Sakura?
Yeah, she's
practicing her heart out.
Oh.
It's her brother
that's the problem.
He's been taking his frustrations
out on the first-year boys.
What frustrations?
From what I hear, he got shot
down pretty hard by Tohsaka.
By Tohsaka?
Keep your voice down!
Anyway, Shinji's been in a
foul mood ever since yesterday.
I've had to keep an eye on him all
through practice, so I'm exhausted.
Yeah, Shinji does
have a nasty temper.
I feel like he might be planning to
get even with Tohsaka somehow.
Nah, not even Shinji would go anywhere
near someone who'd rejected him.
But he can't avoid her
if she comes to him.
I'm not sure why, but Tohsaka's been
coming to watch at the dojo a lot lately.
I guess you didn't know,
since you quit and all.
But man, the look on
his face was hilarious!
He practically pissed his pants!
When Shinji gets
mad, he stays that way.
Hey, you there!
I hate to break it
to you, Matou Shinji,
but Tohsaka Rin isn't gonna turn
up, no matter how long you wait!
Maki, this guy doesn't match the
description Lady Mitsuzuri gave.
He doesn't have
wavy hair, for one.
Oh yeah? I bet he just
slicked it back with a little water!
A face this stupid-looking
could only belong to Matou Shinji!
You've got the wrong guy.
See what I mean? That's
what the culprit always says.
Wait.
Sorry, but would you mind
showing us your student ID?
S-Sure.
Name - Shirou Emiya - Class - 2-C - Issued 4/1 -
The aforementioned is a student of this institution.
Homurahara Academy
See? It's not him, Maki-chan.
Emiya? That Emiya?
The guy who fixes our gear
whenever he has a spare moment?
The one they call
"Homurahara's Brownie"?
I've never heard that nickname before,
but I do know the track and field captain.
Sorry. It seemed like you were looking
for someone, so we just assumed.
That's okay. What was that
about Tohsaka not coming?
Did something happen?
She stayed home today.
Yeah. Tohsaka's taking the
day off with a cold, good sir.
It's hard to believe that
a flawless model student
like her could even
get sick, though, right?
We're sorry for the trouble our circus
attraction here caused you, Emiya.
But you shouldn't
be here, either.
Weren't you told that students with no
club activities should go straight home?
Did something happen?
You didn't know?
There was a homicide by
the intersection near school.
A family of four was attacked,
and only the youngest child survived.
The parents and older
sister were stabbed to death.
The killer is still at large,
and the nature of the killings
has sparked considerable unrest.
In Shinto, they've
got those gas leaks,
while over here, we've got
these gruesome murders.
It's only natural they'd be
sending students home early.
DO NOT CROSS
I know...
Helping others and being a champion
of justice aren't the same thing.
Ah, I see.
Thank you.
Hello.
You must be Shirou-kun.
I'll get straight to the point.
Would you rather
be sent off to an
orphanage, or taken in
by a man you just met?
I'm glad.
Then let's get you
dressed right away.
You should get acclimated to
your new home as soon as possible.
Oh, I forgot to
mention something.
It's important that
you know this, all right?
Well...
For starters,
I'm a magician.
I've still got some
time before work.
You're alive...
You're alive! You're alive!
Thank you. Thank you!
I'm so glad I found someone.
By saving even one person,
I've saved myself.
All I remember of that day ten years ago is
that it was hot, that I couldn't breathe,
and that many others tried to save
people, only to die in the process.
I hate that.
It makes me angry to see
people die after trying so hard.
Is it greedy of me to wish for a
happy ending, full of smiles for all?
It's not that simple.
Because that would involve saving
everyone without exception, Shirou.
Kiritsugu's answer never
really convinced my younger self.
After all, I knew he was an all-powerful
magician who had saved my life.
So I asked Kiritsugu if he could
have saved everyone back then.
But he said...
Shirou.
Saving one person
means not saving another.
You see, a person can only save those
who are on the side they've chosen to take.
It should be obvious, right?
I mean, that's the very
definition of a champion of justice.
I understand that now.
Yeah, it is obvious... But...
But I still hate it.
Salvation shouldn't apply to
a limited number of people.
I can't bear the thought of more strangers
dying around me like they did that day.
That was Tohsaka just now...
wasn't it?
You shoulda said so sooner!
If it's ramen you want, you've
come to the right person!
Really, now?
I happen to be an
expert on ramen!
Where's Sakura?
She went home early tonight.
Why'd you send
her home by herself?
Weren't you saying it wasn't
safe to go out alone at night?
It's fine, it's fine. I sent
one of my men with her.
You should've gone yourself.
You're our teacher, after all.
If I did that, I wouldn't get
to eat dinner until after ten!
It's your fault for staying out
so late at your job, anyway!
I always have to sit here
starving whenever you have work.
If you're so hungry, why can't you
just get dinner at your own house?
But this is my house.
Sheesh.
What's this?
Oh, someone gave that to me,
but I don't want it, so you can have it!
Why, thank you.
But I don't want it either!
You're sadly mistaken if you think
you can hit me with skills like yours.
If you don't like it, I suggest
you practice some more.
But more importantly,
Shirou, I'm famished!
I've been waiting for ages,
so hurry up and make dinner!
Yeah, yeah.
Senpai, I won't be able to help with
the cooking for a while starting tonight.
Is that all right?
Don't worry about it.
It's the weekend, after all.
I'm sure you have
people to hang out with.
No, it's not like that!
It's really just a personal thing,
and I'll still be going to club practices,
so if anything comes up, please come
to the dojo, and I'll see what I can do!
I wouldn't go out and have fun
just because it's the weekend!
So... I'd appreciate it if you
didn't get the wrong idea.
Understood.
If something comes
up, I'll stop by the dojo.
Thanks. That would be great.
Senpai! Your hand!
Where'd this come from?
Did I cut myself while I was
tinkering with some old junk?
It doesn't hurt or anything,
so it should fade soon.
I'm fine. Nothing
to worry about.
Okay. If you say so.
Maybe I'm just tired.
With your efforts, it looks like we'll have
all the equipment fixed before exams begin.
Thank you again for your help.
No problem. See you later.
You think that was amazing?
Shinji.
Still at school, Emiya?
I need to talk to you.
Come with me for a minute.
A minute? Sorry.
As you can see, I don't
have a minute to spare.
Whatever your little
problem is, it can wait.
Isn't that right, girls?
Hang on, Shinji.
This is about the
bruise on Sakura's wrist.
What's this about Sakura?
Don't dodge the question.
You hurt her again, didn't you?
I don't know what you're
talking about, and I don't care.
She's your sister, you know.
Look, Emiya.
You're starting to
get on my nerves.
Yeah, we're brother
and sister, so that's all the
more reason to mind
your own business, isn't it?
You really don't
know how she got it?
Nope.
Or did Sakura tell
you that I beat her?
No.
There you go, then.
It's not nice to make
baseless accusations, Emiya.
I suppose. I'm sorry
I suspected you.
If you're sorry, prove
it by doing me a favor.
See, the dojo's in kind
of a mess right now.
If you've got time to play
the concerned citizen,
maybe you could do
something about it, Emiya-kun?
Didn't Fujimura-sensei tell
you to clean it up, Senpai?
That's right. You'd better...
It's fine.
I mean, if I start cleaning now, the
shop will be closed by the time I finish.
Take it from here, will you?
Wait, Senpai!
We'll leave it to you, then.
Man, this place never changes.
Done.
Who are they?
Who's there?
Hey.
Today just wasn't
your lucky day, boy.
Now that you're a
witness, I can't let you live.
Dead men tell no
tales, and all that.
Curse with your dying breath that you
were born with no luck and no power.
You've given me some dirty work.
How can I call myself
a hero after this?
I understand. I'm
not complaining.
I got a good look
at the girl's Servant.
I'll be a good boy and return.
Jeez. My Master's a
real nasty piece of work.
He's not going to make it.
Not with a skewered heart.
Don't do this to me...
Why did it have to be you?
Why did you have to pick this
hour, on this day, to be here?
No. There's still a way.
What happened?
The man in blue
and the man in red...
Who were those two?
They were far beyond
ordinary humans.
So I really was almost killed.
No.
Not "almost". I was killed.
But here I am, alive.
I was saved by someone
who came along afterward.
Who could it have been?
I wish I could at
least thank them.
And here I was trying
to be considerate. I
figured it'd hurt less if
you never saw it coming.
Can't believe I got stuck with killing
the same person twice in one day.
I guess the world's a bloody
place, no matter what the era.
Trace on.
Make sure you go into
the light this time, boy.
Reinforcing
auxiliary components.
That's an odd style.
It's faint, but I sense mana.
So that's why you're still alive after
taking my spear through your heart.
This might be fun after all.
I gave you a chance, but
you went and wasted it.
If you're a man,
show some dignity.
Checkmate.
That last move was
pretty surprising, boy.
I don't get it, though.
You think fast on your feet,
but you're hopeless at magic.
You seem to have
potential, though.
Maybe you were
meant to be the seventh.
Well, even if you were,
this is the end for you.
Screw you!
My life was saved.
My life was saved, so I'm
not going to give it up so easily!
I need to live. I
have to fulfill my duty.
And I can't do that if I'm dead!
I'm not gonna die for no
reason in a place like this,
killed by a guy like you
who takes lives
like it's nothing!
The seventh Servant?
I ask of you.
Are you my Master?
"Master"?
I, the Saber-class Servant, have
come in response to your summons.
Master, your orders.
Henceforth, you hold
my sword in your hands,
and I hold your fate in mine.
Our contract is thus formed.
What do you mean, "contract"?
You coward!
Why do you conceal
your own weapon?
What's the matter,
Lancer? No self-respecting
spearman stays
rooted to the spot.
If you will not come to
me, I shall come to you!
Before that, let me
ask you one thing.
Your Noble Phantasm:
is it a sword?
Who can say?
It may be a battle axe.
Or perhaps it is a spear.
Or it might even
be a bow, Lancer.
Very funny, swordswoman!
That stance...
One more question.
Since this is our first meeting,
would you be interested
in calling it a draw?
I think not.
You will fall here, Lancer!
Is that so?
A shame. I was only
ordered to observe.
I'll have your heart!
Gae...
Bolg!
So you escaped my
mightiest blow, Saber.
A curse?
No, an attack that
reverses cause and effect?
Gae Bolg...
You are Ireland's
Child of Light!
I messed up.
If I use that
move, it has to kill.
My lord is a coward, you see.
You dodged my spear,
so he's ordering me home.
You would run?
You're more than
welcome to follow me.
But if you do, be
prepared to die!
Wait, Lancer!
I-Is she crazy?
Hey, are you all right?
What the hell are you?
As you can see, I am
a Saber-class Servant.
As such, please call me "Saber".
I'm Shirou.
Emiya Shirou.
Emiya...
This house...
No, that's not right. That
isn't what I want to ask you.
I understand.
You're not a legitimate
Master, are you?
Nonetheless, you are my Master.
Hang on. Isn't it kinda weird to start
calling me "Master" out of the blue?
I shall call you "Shirou", then.
Yes. I much prefer
the way that sounds.
Wh-What are these?
They are called Command Spells.
Do try to avoid
using them carelessly.
Shirou, my wounds,
if you please.
You're asking me?
Sorry, but complicated
magic like that is beyond me.
I shall face them in my
current condition, then.
There are two enemies outside.
One more battle should
not pose a problem.
Enemies outside?
What do you mean?
Stop, Saber!
Are you mad, Shirou?
I could have defeated them
handily, and you ordered me to stop!
Just hold on, Saber!
I have no idea what's going on.
If I'm your Master,
at least fill me in!
You would demand such a
thing with the enemy before us?
Ah, so that's how it is,
my good novice Master?
For starters, good evening,
Emiya-kun.
We didn't understand anything
My left hand groped for
things that vanished to my touch
A moral conflict
stays your hand
and tricks you
out of your future
I don't know how
to protect anyone,
and my ideals might
well be pointless,
but I want to live my life
The past repeats before my eyes
Here I will trust the me
that now stands with you
Until my dream
crumbles and withers,
I hope you will carve
out paradise with me
Fight your fate
I have no reason to fight.
He's a certified
phony, that priest.
Shirou is my Master.
Berserker?
Will you participate
in the Holy Grail War?
Make your decision,
Emiya Shirou.
The Curtain Rises
Next Time